# MAX LEPPER

Electronic Controls Specialist

#### **PROFILE**

Versatile developer of mobile electronic control systems from the Industrial sector with 5 years of experience. Developed "full stack" of a highly modular cement mixer platform interfacing 9 different truck line manufacturers and supporting 4 control configurations and 18 unique accessory packages, with 800+ active vehicles in the field.

#### CONTACT

Phone: 937-369-0086

Email: maxllepper@gmail.com

Location: Dayton, OH

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/maxlepper/ GitLab: gitlab.com/maxlepper

### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

- JavaScript
- · HTML, CSS
- IEC 61131-3 Languages
- CANopen and J1939 communication

## SOFTWARE / PLATFORMS

- · Visual Studio Code
- CoDeSys 2.3/3.5
- Subversion (SVN)
- · Microsoft Suite

## **AWARDS & COMPETITIONS**

Scott Industrial GW Hoffman Technical Excellence (2019)

 Highest technical award at Scott Industrial

Festo International Coding Challenge (2019)

28<sup>th</sup> Finalist

Scott Industrial Officer's Awards (2017, 2014)

 Excellence with Cement Mixer project, documentation

Eagle Scout

# **CERTIFICATIONS**

Software Project Managment Specialization Coursera, May 2020

# **EDUCATION**

Associate of Applied Science in Mechanical Engineering Technology Sinclair Community College, 2011

#### **EXPERIENCE**

Mobile Electronic Controls Specialist

October 2015 – Present

Scott Industrial Systems / Dayton, OH / (937) 438-3171

- Architect and develop complete mobile electronic controls solutions
- Involved in all phases of the software/hardware development life cycle
- Utilize multiple software languages and software suites to create networks of inter-communicating devices to best meet client needs and preferences
- Implement various forms of operator input hardware to deliver functional and approachable system controls for both new and existing operators
- Design, create graphical elements, and develop underlying logic for HMI screens to allow system control, safety, diagnostics, maintenance, and vehicle reporting in an understandable, concise, and user-friendly experience
- Travel with sales team to clients for requirements elicitation and to identify further sales opportunities to grow business relationships
- Travel to customers to provide prototype demonstrations, on-site start-up, product support, and troubleshooting to ensure client satisfaction and product performance
- Produce documentation for software requirements, project scope, project specifications, quotes, and agreements for sales team and customers to validate our product solutions
- Manage and document all projects and tasks to generate reports, gain work time insights, refine delivery estimates based on velocity, and increase visibility on project progress to improve the quality of work being done and aid future development
- Conduct product administration training for clients and product operation training for operators and maintenance personnel to build collaborative relationships and increase product familiarity
- Manage procurement to assemble complete system install packages and preconfigured kits to simplify product delivery and installation
- Switch between numerous projects and tasks rapidly and accurately to move projects forward and quickly respond to customer needs
- Maintain previous responsibilities as Lead Drafter when needed, and for complex or high-accuracy assemblies in AutoCAD and Autodesk Inventor

Lead Drafter (Drafter IV)

October 2013 - October 2015

Scott Industrial Systems / Dayton, OH / (937) 438-3171

Sales Associate

October 2011 - October 2013

The Cellular Connection / Centerville, OH / (937) 848-4172